Contact

iycetee@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/iyesata-conteh-rn-bsn-778b8137 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Eclipse

Cerner

Nursing

Languages

Creoles and pidgins, English-based (Full Professional)

Iyesata Conteh, RN, BSN

Travel cath Lab Nurse at OMC

Greater Atlanta Area

Summary

I am a dedicated, integrity motivated nurse, compassionate with very strong clinical background in critical care settings, with over thirty years' experience in providing high quality care to patients presenting with diverse acute and chronic medical conditions. Highly respected by colleagues for my ability to remain calm in emergency situations, collaborative teamwork, and exhibit superior competency in complex medical procedures. Very experienced in multitasking with emphasis in prioritizing in meeting patient care and family needs. Proficient and experienced in a wide knowledge of the nursing process of assessment, diagnosis, planning, implementation and evaluation of acute, chronic, and complex conditions. Highly capable to perform the physical and sensory requirements of job within the scope of practice, and successfully complete orientation of job performance as needed.

Experience

OMC

Travel cath Lab Nurse March 2020 - Present (4 months)

SJHMC

Travel cath lab nurse February 2019 - December 2019 (11 months)

GHS

Travel Cath Lab Nurse March 2018 - February 2019 (1 year)

Greater Atlanta Area

Christiana Care Health System
Cath lab RN
October 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 3 months)

Newark, Delaware

University of Pennsylvania healthcare system Critical Care Nurse August 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 3 months) Greater Philadelphia Area

Emory Healthcare Registerd Nurse August 1989 - July 2014 (25 years)

Emory University Hospital Critical Care Registered Nurse August 1989 - July 2014 (25 years) Atlanta

As a charge nurse, I supervised nursing staff to deliver optimal patient care for positive patient outcomes using evidence based practices. Coordinates and direct the daily care of patients' needs in the critical setting according to acuity of patient to level of experience of staff. Daily goal is fostering optimal patient care delivery for positive patient outcomes.

Assists physicians proficiently with all invasive procedures and interventions, such as intubations, GI procedures, tracheostomy, and conscious sedation monitoring, invasive line insertions. Performs proficiently in cardiac and/ or respiratory arrests, hemodynamic monitoring, and exhibits excellent organizational and customer service skills with a focus on patient and family.

Implements total patient care in a Level 1 ICU by acting as a patient advocate, continually assessing patient's status, and notifying physicians of any clinical changes.

Proficient with computerized Physician Order Entry in coordinating service, treatments, and consultations using E.E.M.R, Cerner, Epic, Emstat, Eclipsys computation.

Precepts and mentor for students and new nurses to demonstrate nursing care and with new employees ensuring adequate orientation. Actively participates in teaching yearly critical care skills for Emory critical care division. Provides comprehensive, ethical, and independent decision-making proficiency consistent with facility protocols.

"Super-user" of several medical devices and monitors:

Provides a continuous and supportive learning environment to colleagues, including being a role model for evidence-based nursing practice; providing feedback to the health team and collaborating in the decision making process and supported clinical skill development.

Piedmont Healthcare

9 years 1 month

Registered Nurse

May 2005 - May 2014 (9 years 1 month)

Fayetteville, Georgia

Performs proficiently in triage, assessment and intervention of the ED process.

Collaborating effectively with other healthcare team in providing optimal patient care delivery of acute and chronic patient conditions.

RN at Piedmont Fayette ED May 2005 - 2014 (9 years)

Education

Lamar University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse

National School of Nursing

Associate of Science (AS), Nursing · (1980 - 1983)

Lamar University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing